Guide to the James Boyd Collection of New York City Etchings 1861-1940, undated (bulk, 1910-1939) PR 7
New-York Historical Society
James Boyd collection of New York City etchings
1861-1940, undated (bulk, 1910-1939)
New-York Historical Society
Boyd, James, 1864-1947
PR 7
8.58 Linear feet (7 boxes, 508 prints)
Collection of etchings by New York City artists depicting the city. Subjects include major skyscrapers and other buildings, street scenes, neighborhoods, harbors, bridges, and views from high vantage points.
Access Restrictions
Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of James Boyd in 1935 through 1944, in memory of his wife, Agnes Gray Boyd.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. New York City Etchings
Oversize Material from Series I
Series II. Accompanying material
Biographical Note
James Boyd was born in 1864 into a family of Manhattan candle makers; he was the fourth generation to work in the business. Boyd received his early education at Chapin Collegiate School, graduating from the University of the City of New York (New York University) in 1882. He was awarded an honorary doctorate in philosophy by Washington College in Tennessee. From 1882 to 1891, Boyd assisted his father in the family business. The firm, established as James Boyd in 1819, became James Boyd's Sons, James Boyd's Son, and finally James Boyd once again. In 1925, Boyd dissolved the firm due to sluggish sales. In 1890, Boyd became a member of the New York Produce Exchange. Other affiliations included a fellowship in the New-York Historical Society and membership in the University Club. He served on the Council of New York University and He served for many years as treasurer of the General Society of Mechanics and Tradesmen. James Boyd died at age 83 on February 13, 1947. Agnes Gray Boyd, his wife, died on January 16, 1935.
Related Materials
Additional prints of New York City scenes by Boyd Collection artists (and other artists) can be found in PR 229 Fine Art Prints of New York City, and PR 035 Herman Lieberman Jr. Collection of Wall Street Prints. One watercolor that came with the Boyd etchings, "The Narrowest House in New York City - 75 1/2 Bedford Street," by Syd Browne (Boyd no. 486), was transferred to the N-YHS museum collection in 2004.
Scope and Contents
In 1935, James Boyd presented to the Society 460 prints (primarily, but not all, etchings) by 61 artists (primarily, but not all, American), given in memory of his wife. He added to the collection through 1944, bringing the total to 508 items. The prints are now arranged by artist, and thereunder by the "Boyd number" (from 1 to 508) in the order in which they were accessioned. The Boyd numbers appear in parentheses following the title of the print.
The prints depict the towering city of the decades between 1910 and 1935: the Empire State Building and other major skyscrapers, the Wall Street area and other street scenes, various Manhattan neighborhoods and churches, the New York harbor, East River bridges, the George Washington Bridge, and views from high vantage points. What sets this corpus of late-nineteenth-century/early-modern prints apart is its inclusion of "second tier" artists, whose work adds to the spectrum of printmaking in New York during the first half of the twentieth century.
Artists well represented in the original gift include Anton Schutz (121); William C. McNulty (35); and Edith Nankivell (31). Artists with more than one print include John Taylor Arms, G. L. Briem, Kerr Eby, William Ferrari, Jack Fischer, Paul Geissler, William Heyer, F. Leo Hunter, Nat Lowell, Charles W. Mielatz, H. Loren Mills, Fugi Nakamizo, B.J.O. Nordfeldt, Joseph Pennell, Will J. Quinlan, Ernest D. Roth, Louis Schmidt, Paul Simonsen, John Sloan, Bernhardt Wall, W. H. Wallace, and Elisha K. K. Wetherill.
The collection also includes material from Boyd's own files: two letters (1927, 1928) from French print dealer Louis Godefroy to Boyd; New York (1927-33) and Paris (1927-31) print exhibition catalogs; four art periodicals (1899-1929); and one photograph (1933) of artist William McNulty in his studio.
Etchings (prints); Prints (visual works).; New York (N.Y.) -- Buildings, structures, etc. -- Pictorial works.; New York (N.Y.) -- Pictorial works.; New York (N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- Pictorial works.; Streets -- New York (State) -- New York.; Arms, John Taylor, 1887-1953; Borne, Mortimer; Boyd, James, 1864-1947 -- collector; Briem, Gottlob L.; Browne, Syd, 1907-; Eby, Kerr, 1890-1946; Ferrari, William; Fischer, Jack; Geissler, Paul; Heyer, William; Hunter, F. Leo; Lowell, Nat; McNulty, William Charles, 1884-1963; Meilatz, Charles F. W.; Mills, H. Loren; Nakamizo, Fugi; Nankivell, Edith; Nordfeldt, Bror Julius Olsson, 1878-1955; Pennell, Joseph, 1857-1926; Quinlan, Will J.; Roth, Ernest David, 1879-1964; Schmidt, Louis; Schutz, Anton Joseph Friedrich, 1894-1977; Simonsen, Paul; Sloan, John, 1871-1951; Wall, Bernhardt, 1872-1956; Wallace, William Henry, 1838-1929; Wetherill, Elisha Kent Kane, 1874-1929
- Series I: New York City Etchings
  Scope and Contents note
  Prints are arranged alphabetically by artist, then by Boyd inventory number within. (Boyd numbers) follow each title; titles listed are assigned by artist while [descriptions appear in brackets]. All prints are black and white etchings unless otherwise described; dates are given if inscribed by artist or in plate.
  - Arms, John Taylor (1887-1953)
    - [42nd Street looking west from Fifth Avenue] (392) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    - [Manhattan skyline with sailboat, the "Sarah Jane"] color (404), 1920 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    - Croquis, New York [Woolworth Building] (413) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    - [Woolworth Building from arch of Municipal Building] (415) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    - De ma Fenetre (434) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - Asanger, Jacob (1887-1941)
    - [Jenny Lind's home on Washington Square] color (439) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  - Besedick, Frank (1913-87)
    - Palisades [New Jersey] (494) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - Borne, Mortimer (1902-87)
    - The Street Vendors [Hester Street near Essex Street] (144) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    - The Little Church around the Corner (145) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    - [East River from Bellevue] (146) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    - Union Square, N.Y. (147) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    - Fulton Market (148), 1928 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    - Gracie Mansion, Old N.Y. (303), 1927 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Briem, Gottlob L. (1899-1972)
    - Wall St., N.YC. (116), 1931 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - Empire State Bldg, N.Y.C. (117) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - Woolworth [Building] N.Y.C. (118) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - "L" Station - 42nd St. & 3rd Ave. N.Y.C. (119) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - City Bank N.Y.C. & Farmers Trust Co., Wm St. (120) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - 39th St. & 6th Ave. N.Y.C. (121) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - Base of Chrysler Bldg. N.Y.C. (122), 1930 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - Parking Space - 30th Street, N.Y.C. (123) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - Manhattan Trust Co. Bldg. (124) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - Excavation on Wall Street, N.Y.C. (125), 1935 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - 6th Ave. and 33rd St. N.Y.C. (126), 1935 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - Marvel of Technical Science - Washington Memorial Bridge (127) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
    - Marvel of Technical Science - Washington Memorial Bridge (128) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
    - Power - Washington Bridge, New York City (129), 1931 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
    - Tower under construction - Washington Bridge (130), 1931 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
    - Cement and Steel - Washington Memorial Bridge (131) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
    - Chanin Building from Chrysler Building (132) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
    - The River N.Y.C. [from 6th Ave & 39th St. looking east] (133) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
    - Church & Fulton Streets, N.Y.C. (134) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
    - Power - Washington Memorial Bridge (135) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
    - Cement & Steel - Washington Bridge N.Y.C. [first proof] (136) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
  - Browne, Syd J. (1907-91)
    - Old New York. Peck Slip - NY east side (458) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - Long Shore Hauling (in front of Weehawken Ferry) (459), 1935 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - West Washington Market, NY, Gansevoort St., soft ground (460) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - The Float Bridge (from west shore freight yard), soft ground (461), 1935 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - Chinatown, N.Y. - Doyer Street, drypoint (462) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - The Fortune Teller (1st Avenue & 13th St. NY), drypoint (463), 1934 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - East Side Market, N.Y. (1st Ave. at 11th St. N.Y.), drypoint (464), 1934 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - Greenwich Village, N.Y. (looking north on 6th & Washington Place) (470), 1936 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - Looking Southwest at 138th St. and Harlem River (474), 1937 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - The River Road (475) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - Sutton Place, East River, New York (476) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - West and Christopher St. (477), 1937 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
    - James Slip, New York (484), 1938 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
    - James Slip Gospel Mission (485) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
    - Along the Freight Tracks (50th St. Between 10th & 11th Avenues) (491), 1939 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
    - Lower New York (492), 1940 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
    - Grove St., Greenwich Village (493), 1933 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
    - East River Docks (496), 1940 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
  - Chamberlain, Samuel (1895-1975)
    - The Curving Canyon, New York, drypoint (107), 1929 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dehmann, K.
    - [Wall Street and New York Stock Exchange] (27) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)
  - Detwiller, Frederick K. (1882-1953)
    - Building the Nave - Cathedral of St. John the Divine (16), 1925 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
    - Passways from Manhattan, July 4, Williamsburg Bridge (505), 1924 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
    - Key Hole to a City June 4, 1933 Williamsburg Bridge (506) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
    - Williamsburg Bridge, from Brooklyn, July 4, 1924 (507) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
    - Pylons, Hudson River Bridge, view between 176th and 177th Sts. (508), 1928 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
      General note
      See: Box 6, Folder 91
  - Deville, Henri (French 1871-?; active in US 1902-14)
    - Pine Street [canyon] (57), 1910 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12)
    - [Street scene with Singer Building] (311) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12)
    - Broadway south of 42nd Street (357) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12)
  - Dolice, Louis
    - China-town N.Y.C. [Doyers Street] (318), 1922 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 13)
    - Union Square [looking northwest from 15th Street] (358), 1923 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 13)
    - Little Church around the Corner (360), 1922 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 13)
  - Doniphan, A.
    - An Antique Shop, 29th street near Broadway (319), 1917 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 14)
    - Little Church around the Corner (334), 1919 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 14)
  - Drewes, Werner (1899-1985)
    - [Empire State Building] (185), 1931 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
    - [St. Bartholomew's Church and Waldorf-Astoria] (186), 1931 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
    - [Empire State Building from west side] (187), 1931 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
    - [River House at East River] (188), 1931 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
    - [Columbus Circle] (189), 1931 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
    - 50th Street & 3rd Avenue (190), 1931 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
    - Central Park [looking southeast toward Fifth Avenue] (193) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
      See: Box 6. Folder 92
    - Lower Manhattan Seen from Montague Terrace (194) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
    - Wall Street (195) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
  - Eby, Kerr (1890-1946)
    - [No. 1 Wall Street] (2) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 16)
    - [George Washington Bridge] (48) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 16)
    - [Burns Bros. coal yard, Sutton Place] (406) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 16)
  - Ferrari, William
    - Woolworth Building [through Municipal Building arch] (173) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 17)
    - Plaza Towers (174) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 17)
    - Ritz Tower (175) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 17)
    - Broad and William [Beaver?] Sts. (176) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 17)
    - Grand Central, north from 41st Street (330), 1929 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 17)
    - Stock Exchange, Broad Street (379), 1929 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 17)
    - Plaza Towers (387) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 17)
  - Fischer, Jack
    - Riverside Church, color (180) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
    - White Way - Times Square looking north, color (181) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
    - Battery Park (182), 1930 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
    - Gramercy Park, color (183) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
    - Lower Broadway seen from the Battery, color (184) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
    - [Lower Manhattan, East River, Brooklyn Bridge] color (202) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
    - [Empire State Building] color (203) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
    - [Plaza Towers from Central Park] color (204) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
    - [George Washington Bridge] color (205) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
    - Financial Towers, color (206) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 18)
  - French, E.D.
    - Six Views of Early New York Fort New Amsterdam (New York) 1651 New York in 1671 New York in 1673 New York in 1733 City of New York during the Revolutionary War New York in 1801, ca. 1940 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 19)
  - Gallagher, Sears
    - [New York Stock Exchange] (400) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 20)
  - Geissler, Paul
    - The East River (4) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 21)
      See: Box 6, Folder 93
    - Off for Foreign Ports [New York harbor] (5) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 21)
    - [Lower Broadway] (18) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 21)
    - [Woolworth Building] (19), 1928 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 21)
    - [Bowling Green] (38), 1928 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 21)
    - Towering Hotels at Central Park, New York (92) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 21)
    - New York Stock Exchange (94) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 21)
    - Towers of Commerce (New York) (97) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 21)
    - The Battery and West Street (356), 1929 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 21)
  - Grossman, Elias M.
    - New York Harbor, soft ground (74) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 22)
  - Hassam, Childe (1859-1935)
    - [Fifth Avenue] (448), 1914 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 23)
  - Heyer, William
    - [East River view] (353) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 24)
    - [Boat builders along the Hudson River] (354) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 24)
    - [Brooklyn and Manhattan bridges, Brooklyn rooftops] (383) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 24)
    - [Brooklyn, with bridge tower] (384) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 24)
  - Hollyer, Samuel
    - Fraunces Tavern (251) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 25)
  - Hoppe, W.
    - [Lower Manhattan skyline from Governors' Island] (305) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 26)
    - [Library of Columbia University (old)] (328) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 26)
    - [Statue of Liberty] (329) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 26)
    - [Soldiers and Sailors Monument, Riverside Drive] (332) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 26)
    - [Woolworth Building from the west] (414) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 26)
  - Hunter, F[rederick] Leo (1862-1943)
    - Coenties Slip N.Y. (232), 1881 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 27)
    - Coenties Slip, South Street, N.Y. (236), 1881 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 27)
    - At the Foot of Wall Street, N.Y. (237), 1879 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 27)
    - Old Houses - Houston Street, New York (238), 1879 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 27)
    - Banker's Trust Company Building looking east (239) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 27)
      See: Box 6, Folder 94
    - [Wall Street, toward Trinity Church] (240), 1903 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 27)
    - Old Dyckman House, N.Y. (241), 1889 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 27)
    - South and DePeyster Streets (242), 1879 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 27)
    - Old Steamship Row, New York, N.Y. (293), 1881 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 27)
    - Burling Slip, N.Y. [c. 1921] (294), 1881 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 27)
    - Coenties Slip, N.Y. [c. 1921] (295), 1878 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 27)
    - Old Slip, New York, N.Y. [c. 1921] (296), 1878 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 27)
    - The Old East India Wharf, N.Y. [c. 1921] (297), 1879 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 28)
    - South Street, south of Burling Slip (298), 1879 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 28)
    - Bowling Green (299), 1921 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 28)
    - Coenties Slip [copyright 1921] (300), 1878 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 28)
    - Peck Slip, New York, N.Y. [c. 1921] (380), 1879 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 28)
    - At the foot of Maiden Lane, New York, N.Y. [c. 1921] (381), 1881 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 28)
    - Burling Slip, N.Y. [c. 1921] (385), 1881 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 28)
    - The Old Hudson Tavern [Hudson & Desbrosses Sts.] (386), 1879 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 28)
    - Banker's Trust Company's Building (388) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 28)
    - Old Slip, N.Y. (389), 1878 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 28)
    - New York University - Washington Square [c. 1924] (430), 1880 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 28)
    - Old East India Wharf, New York (449), 1885 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 28)
  - K., A. (unknown artist, all linocuts or wood engravings)
    - [New York Stock Exchange from Federal Hall steps] (196) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 29)
    - [View along Wall Street toward Trinity Church] (197) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 29)
    - [Broad Street canyon] (198) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 29)
    - [Plaza Towers from Central Park] (199) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 29)
    - [Pershing Square, Park Avenue, Grand Central] (200) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 29)
    - [Brooklyn Bridge, East River shore] (201) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 29)
  - Karoly, Andrew
    - The Woolworth Building (209) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 30)
    - Wall Street, New York (210) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 30)
    - New York [boat loading] (211), 1928 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 30)
    - The City Hall (377) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 30)
  - Laboureur, Jean-Emile (1877-1943)
    - Broadway, New-York [Herald Square] (248), 1907 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 31)
  - Le Riche, Henri (b. 1868)
    - [Trinity Church] (212) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 32)
    - [Madison Square Garden, Madison Square] (213) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 32)
    - [Manhattan Skyline] (447) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 32)
    - [Trinity Church] (495) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 32)
  - Lowell, Nat
    - The Little Church around the Corner (32), 1928 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 33)
    - Grand Central Station (423), 1929 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 33)
    - The Little Church around the Corner (139), 1928 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 33)
  - McNulty, William C. (1889-1963)
    - New Pants - Orchard St., N.Y. (9), 1933 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 34)
    - Orchard St., N.Y. (10), 1933 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 34)
    - Orchard St., N.Y. [later state of no. 10] (11), 1933 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 34)
    - After the Storm - New York from Stevens Institute, Hoboken, N.J. (13), 1934 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 34)
    - Towers in the Sun, N.Y. [55th St. and 1st Ave.] (14), 1933 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 34)
    - The Orange Cart - Orchard St. N.Y. (15) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 34)
    - Docks, Fulton Market (17) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 34)
    - The Blacksmith at Spuyten Duyvil (21), 1931 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 34)
    - Demolishing Old Madison Square Garden (22), 1927 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 34)
    - Brooklyn from Wall - N.Y. (23), 1930 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 34)
    - Fifth Avenue Hotels, N.Y. (24), 1930 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 35)
    - Fifth Ave. Hotels [trial proof] (25), 1930 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 35)
    - Wall Street, N.Y. (26), 1930 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 35)
    - The Bridges - From Top of Royal Insurance Bldg. [trial; 2nd state] (28) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 35)
    - Demolishing the Century Theatre, Central Park West & 61st St. (30), 1931 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 35)
    - Under Brooklyn Bridge, N.Y. (31), 1931 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 35)
    - Plaza Square N.Y. [Fifth Avenue at 59th St.] (37), 1928 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 35)
    - Plaza Square (41) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 35)
    - New York Stock Exchange (42) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 35)
    - Times Square, N.Y. (44) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 35)
    - Waldorf Astoria Hotel, N.Y. (Fifth Ave. and 34th St.) (45) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 36)
    - New York in the Fifties (@ 56th & 6th Ave. - from Hotel Devon) (80) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 36)
    - New York from Governor's Island (85), 1930 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 36)
    - Coenties Slip, N.Y. (100), 1929 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 36)
    - Woolworth Building, New York (101), 1929 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 36)
    - Roaring Forties, New York (102), 1929 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 36)
    - 59th Street Lake [Central Park] (142), 1930 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 36)
    - MacDougal Alley looking to Fifth Avenue (252), 1927 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 36)
    - Building with Steel, Paramount Bldg B'way (253), 1926 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 36)
    - Demolishing Madison Square Garden (254), 1927 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 36)
    - Rag Pickers, 30th Street & Hudson River (255), 1926 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 36)
    - Coal Pocket, 30th St & Hudson River (256), 1925 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 37)
    - Death Ave N.Y. City (28th St. & 10th Ave.) (257), 1926 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 37)
    - The Bridges (421), 1934 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 37)
    - Carnegie Hall, N.Y. (427), 1929 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 37)
    - Junk Shop, 302 West 21st St. [and Eighth Ave.] (429), 1925 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 37)
    - Jersey from the Bankers' Club (473), 1930 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 37)
  - Merrick
    - [Washington Square, Judson Memorial Church] (440) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 38)
  - Merrill, Katharine
    - The Union League Club (109) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 39)
  - Mielatz, Charles Frederick William (1864-1919)
    - The (old) Tombs Prison (336), 1889 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 40)
    - Balcony in Pell Street, colored etching (394), 1908 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 40)
    - [Our Bridge of Sighs] (398) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 40)
  - Mills, H. Loren
    - Riverside Drive Park, looking south, 86th St. (46) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 41)
    - Bridge to City Island (149) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 41)
    - The Lake (Central Park Lake at 75th St.) (150) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 41)
    - Top of the Hill (Central Park) (151) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 41)
    - A Winter's Afternoon, Belevedere, Central Park (152) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 41)
  - Monk, W.
    - Metropolitan Tower looking south from 28th St (444) (Box Unknown container 298 for instance of Metropolitan Tower looking south from 28th St (444), Folder unknown container)
      See: Oversize Drawer, folder 97
  - Nakanizo, Fugi
    - The New York Public Library (Fifth Avenue) (327) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 42)
    - [Sherman Statue, Fifth Avenue and 59th Street] (416) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 42)
    - St. Paul's Church (433) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 42)
  - Nankivell, Edith (1896-1984)
    - Union Square (7), 1935 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 43)
    - Old Saint Andrew's, Duane St. (8), 1934 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 43)
    - The Little Church Around the Corner (12) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 43)
    - Zeta Psi House, New York University, University Heights (20) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 43)
    - Jefferson Market Court (61), 1927 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 43)
    - Hall of Fame, [New York University] University Heights (84) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 43)
    - Grand Central Station, looking north (87), 1930 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 43)
    - Chelsea Cottages (W. 24th St., no 424 et seq.) (112) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 43)
    - London Terrace (431 W. 23 St in foreground) (113), 1923 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 43)
    - [Chelsea Cottages (438 & 440 W. 24th St)] (114), 1929 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 43)